<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Culture on The Frassati Society</title>
    <link>http://frassatisociety.org/tags/culture/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Culture on The Frassati Society</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 21:29:20 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://frassatisociety.org/tags/culture/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Steelmanning Modernist Music &amp; A Rebuttal</title>
      <link>http://frassatisociety.org/blog/2026/01/19/steelmanning-modern-music/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 21:29:20 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://frassatisociety.org/blog/2026/01/19/steelmanning-modern-music/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;With the previous article on sacred music, it seems prudent to look at how it applies to the state of the current perspectives of liturgical changes. In intellectual discourse, steelmanning means presenting the strongest possible version of an opponent’s argument before critiquing it. Unlike strawmanning, which attacks a weak caricature, steelmanning engages with the best evidence and reasoning available.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Here, we’ll steelman the case for including nontraditional music, guitar-led hymns, and contemporary worship songs in the Mass. Proponents argue these align with Vatican II’s vision for a vibrant, participatory liturgy, citing Church documents and papal statements. We will analyze whether current practices are in line with these teachings.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Unnecessary End of the Male Life Cycle</title>
      <link>http://frassatisociety.org/blog/2025/07/29/end-of-man/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2025 21:29:20 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://frassatisociety.org/blog/2025/07/29/end-of-man/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-comfort-crisis&#34;&gt;The Comfort Crisis&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There is a creeping complacency in our modern age—a desire to be comfortable, non-confrontational, and liked. This comfort masquerades as virtue, particularly in how we understand manhood. The feminization of the culture has also overtaken traditional circles, erasing the masculine excellence that they purport to be the heralds of.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Many conservatives, like Charlie Kirk and Tucker, now parrot a secularized version of Christian marriage, even if this is not their intention this is the effect. They state the most impactful thing a man can do is “get married and have children,” as if procreation alone were the ultimate end of man’s purpose, rather than a means ordered toward something higher. This view has reduced marriage to a consumerist product: a way to feel complete, settle down, to fulfill a personal dream. But in truth, marriage is a sacrament, a mission—a crucible of sanctification, not a retreat from the battle.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Against Contraception in All Its Forms</title>
      <link>http://frassatisociety.org/blog/2025/03/31/against-all-contraception/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Mar 2025 21:29:20 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://frassatisociety.org/blog/2025/03/31/against-all-contraception/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We live in a contraceptive culture, and the condoms are just a little snowflake on top of the life-hating iceberg.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-tale-of-grass&#34;&gt;The Tale of Grass&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Wednesday I ran into a group reading Marc Barnes’ lovely piece on counterproductivity. Once upon a time, we cut the grass to feed it to cows - now, we cut it even more frequently with zero productivity. The peasants got hay in return for their workout - in return for our spent gasoline and fertilizer, we get hearing damage.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
