<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Spirituality on The Frassati Society</title>
    <link>https://frassati.blonocatholic.com/categories/spirituality/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Spirituality on The Frassati Society</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2025 21:29:20 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://frassati.blonocatholic.com/categories/spirituality/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Unnecessary End of the Male Life Cycle</title>
      <link>https://frassati.blonocatholic.com/blog/2025/07/29/end-of-man/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2025 21:29:20 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://frassati.blonocatholic.com/blog/2025/07/29/end-of-man/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-comfort-crisis&#34;&gt;The Comfort Crisis&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There is a creeping complacency in our modern age—a desire to be comfortable, non-confrontational, and liked. This comfort masquerades as virtue, particularly in how we understand manhood. The feminization of the culture has also overtaken traditional circles, erasing the masculine excellence that they purport to be the heralds of.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Many conservatives, like Charlie Kirk and Tucker, now parrot a secularized version of Christian marriage, even if this is not their intention this is the effect. They state the most impactful thing a man can do is “get married and have children,” as if procreation alone were the ultimate end of man’s purpose, rather than a means ordered toward something higher. This view has reduced marriage to a consumerist product: a way to feel complete, settle down, to fulfill a personal dream. But in truth, marriage is a sacrament, a mission—a crucible of sanctification, not a retreat from the battle.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
